Guide to the Christopher Tunnard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Christopher Tunnard papers
1907-1978
MS 1070
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19
The papers consist of correspondence, topical files, writings, teaching files, and pictorial material which document Christopher Tunnard's career as a landscape designer, city planning consultant, author, and professor of city planning.
Tunnard, Christopher, 1910-1979
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Yale University Art and Architecture Library, 1979, and gift of Christopher Tunnard, 1983.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence and Topical Files, 1921-1978. II. Writings, 1949-1978. III. Teaching Files, 1947-1975. IV. Pictorial Material, 1907-1977.
Scope and Contents
The Christopher Tunnard Papers contain correspondence, topical files, writings, teaching files, and printed and pictorial material which document Tunnard's career as a landscape designer, city planning consultant, author, and professor of city planning. The papers were donated by Tunnard's son Christopher Tunnard in 1983. Layouts for the Inwood Planning Study were transferred from the Yale Art and Architecture Library to Manuscripts and Archives in 1979. The nineteen linear feet of material are arranged in four series: I. CORRESPONDENCE AND TOPICAL FILES, II. WRITINGS, III. TEACHING FILES, IV. PICTORIAL MATERIAL.
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE AND TOPICAL FILES, contains material which documents aspects of Tunnard's professional career. Material of a personal nature within the series consists of biographical sketches and curriculum vitae, fragmentary family correspondence, clippings, memorabilia, and legal and financial documents.
The bulk of the material dates from 1952 to 1975 and includes correspondence relating to his teaching activities at Harvard (predominately after 1945), Yale, and other universities; correspondence with university faculty members and city planning professionals who guest lectured at Yale; and materials relating to Tunnard's administrative activities within the Yale City Planning Department. The series also includes correspondence with publishers of his books and articles; correspondence, printed material, and reports relating to the consulting work Tunnard performed for various city and citizen interest groups; and materials relating to his international research and consulting projects. Correspondents include Henry Hope Reed, Joseph Hudnut, John Pearce, C. McKim Norton, Boris Pushkarev, Richardson Wood, and Coleman Woodbury.
Tunnard's active membership in professional associations is documented by correspondence, newsletters, and reports relating to conferences, local and regional meetings, and special projects. Associations represented in the papers include the American Institute of Architects, the American Institute of Planners, the History of Planning Group, the International Council of Monuments and Sites, the National Trust for Historic Preservation, and the Society of Architectural Historians. New Haven organizations represented in the series include the New Haven City Plan Commission and the New Haven Preservation Trust. These files contain correspondence with New Haven city officials and fellow members of the organizations, and printed material.
Series II, WRITINGS, consists of outlines, notes, drafts, typescripts, galleys, and published copies of Tunnard's books, articles, reviews, speeches, and lectures.
Series III, TEACHING FILES, includes course files which contain syllabi, notes, and lectures from courses taught at Harvard, Yale, and other academic institutions. Because Tunnard interfiled teaching materials he used for similiar courses at various academic institutions, these files have been arranged by generic course titles rather than by specific course numbers and titles. The topic files contain notes and printed matter that complement the materials within the course files. Files of student papers include master's theses, class papers, and projects. Folders containing copies of examination questions and fragmentary notes follow the course and topic files.
Series IV, PICTORIAL MATERIAL, consists of photographs, prints, and drawings used to illustrate A World With a View; materials used to conduct preliminary research and to document UNESCO cultural missions; personal photographs; and miscellaneous illustrative materials relating to Tunnard's professional interests.
Biographical / Historical
Christopher Tunnard was born in Victoria, British Columbia, Canada on July 7, 1910, the son of Christopher Coney and Madeline (Kingscote) Tunnard. He attended St. Michael's School and Victoria College of the University of British Columbia in Canada (1927-1928). From 1928 to 1930 Tunnard studied horticulture and landscape design at the College of the Royal Horticultural Society, Wisley, England, and in 1932 he studied building construction at the Westminster Technical Institute in London.
From 1932 to 1934 Tunnard was employed as a draftsman-designer for the London firm of the garden designer Percy S. Crane. From 1934 to 1937 he had a private practice as a landscape designer and site planner near London at St. Ann's Hill, Surrey. He continued his private practice in London from 1937 until 1939, when he became a visiting lecturer on landscape design and regional planning in the Graduate School of Design at Harvard University. From 1942 to 1943 he served with the Royal Canadian Engineers. Following his discharge from the service he helped make plans for the postwar rebuilding of London as chairman of the town planning committee of the Modern Architectural Research Society of London.
In 1944 Tunnard accepted a teaching position at Yale University. He was a lecturer (1944-1945), assistant professor (1945-1948), associate professor (1948-1962), professor (1962-1975), and professor emeritus (1975-1979) in city planning, and was instrumental in the development of the city planning program at Yale. He was appointed director of the newly created graduate program in city planning in 1950, and was acting chairman of the department of city planning (which was established in 1960) from November 1965 to June 30, 1967, and chairman from July 1967 to 1969.
During his tenure at Yale Tunnard guest lectured at numerous universities, including the University of California at Berkeley, the University of Minnesota, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Clemson College, the University of Illinois, North Carolina State, the University of Winnipeg, the University of Rome, Italy, and Harvard University.
Tunnard is noted for his concept of the "regional city" the idea that the Atlantic seaboard, for example, is not a series of cities along the coastline, but one "super city." He believed that these super cities should be planned as regions rather than individual cities. Tunnard also emphasized the importance of aesthetics in planning, and maintained that civic art and the integration of the natural landscape with new construction were critical to the health and productivity of American urban communities.
Tunnard received a number of grants which supported his research on the American city including a Wheelwright Fellowship in Architecture at Harvard University in 1943, a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1950, and a Rockefeller Foundation grant to direct a three-year program (1957-1959) at Yale to study the design aspects of the regional city.
Tunnard received the Silver Gilt Medal for Landscape Design at the Paris Exposition in 1937. In 1956 he received a Fulbright Research Fellowship to work at the Institut d'Urbanisme at the University of Paris, and in 1961 he received a Fulbright to conduct research and teach at the Academy of Fine Arts in Istanbul, Turkey. He was elected a Fellow of the Royal Society of Arts, London, England in 1966.
As a private consultant Tunnard was involved in the city planning activities of government and citizen interest groups throughout the United States. He also consulted on a number of international projects including UNESCO missions to study historic monuments in Java, Jamaica, and Kathmandu, Nepal, and a city planning project in Barranquilla, Colombia. From 1951 to 1959, Tunnard, Henry Hope Reed, and James Henry Ward were partners in a consulting firm which specialized in city planning. In the 1960s he formed a partnership with fellow Yale city planning faculty member Walter D. Harris.
An active preservationist, Tunnard served as a member of the International Relations Committee of the National Trust for Historic Preservation, the president of the New Haven Preservation Trust, and as a member of the International Council on Monuments and Sites. He was a member of the American Institute of Planners, the American Society of Planning Officials, the American Institute of Architects, the Institute of Landscape Architects, the British Institute of Landscape Architects, and the American Society of Architectural Historians. He was active in the planning activities of the New Haven area community, serving as an appointed member of the New Haven City Plan Commission and the Regional Planning Authority of South Central Connecticut.
His publications include Gardens in the Modern Landscape (1938), The City of Man (1953), American Skyline (with Henry Hope Reed, 1953), Man-Made America: Chaos or Control? (with Boris Pushkarev, 1963), and A World With a View (1978). Tunnard's articles and reviews appeared in publications including Harper's, Journal of the American Institute of Planners, Landscape, Saturday Review of Literature, and Comment.
Tunnard married Lydia Evans of Boston, Massachusetts in 1945. They had a son, Christopher. Tunnard died in New Haven in 1979.
City planning; Historic sites -- Conservation and restoration; Landscape architecture; City planners; Hudnut, Joseph; Norton, C. McKim; Pearce, John N.; Pushkarev, B. S. (Boris Sergeevich), 1929-; Reed, Henry Hope, 1915-2013; Tunnard, Christopher, 1910-1979; Wood, Richardson; Woodbury, Coleman, 1903-1994; New Haven (Conn.). City Plan Commission; American Institute of Architects; American Institute of Planners; International Council of Monuments and Sites; National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States; New Haven Preservation Trust; Society of Architectural Historians; Unesco; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of City Planning; Yale University. School of Art and Architecture. Dept. of Architecture
- CORRESPONDENCE AND TOPICAL FILES, 1921-1978; Series I; 11 linear feet (26 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The material within this series is alphabetically arranged by name of individual, corporate body, or topic. Ten or more items relating to one subject have been arranged chronologically in an individually labelled folder. Fragmentary and unidentified materials are arranged at the end of the series.
  - Ab - Am (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - An - Arc (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ari - Av (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Address lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1945, 1950-1974, 1952-1973, 1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-10)
  - American Skyline
    - Correspondence, 1952-1956, 1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - American Society of Planning Officials, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Annapolis, Maryland, 1962-1965, 1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    General note
    See also: box 42, folder 695
  - Architectural Forum, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ba - Ber (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bet - Bl (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bo - Bro (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bru - Bu (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Barnstone, Howard, 1952, 1957-1959, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Barranquilla, Colombia, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bibliographies, miscellaneous, 1945-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 22-26)
  - Brenner, William, 1969, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bridgeport, Connecticut: civil service exam, 1948-1953, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Horace Huntingdon, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Burgess, Helen, 1964-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    See also: box 12, folders 194-199 See also: box 13, folders 200-202
  - Bury, Richard I., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ca - Ce (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Ch - Cl (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cob - Col (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Com - Con (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Coo - Cu (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Canberra, Australia, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Central New York Architectural Historians, 1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Chapman, F. R., 1957-1959, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - City of Man
    - Complaints; notes; miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Post-publication letters; advance copies letters; requests for copies, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Post-publication letters; advance copies letters; requests for copies, 1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Civic Art Conference, 1950-1952, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Civilizing the American Roadway Conference, 1958, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Classical America, 1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Collier's, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Columbia, Maryland, 1966-1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Conference Board on Associated Research Councils, 1954-1961 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Conference on the City and History, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Conference on the City and History, 1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Congress of Architects and Technicians of Historical Monuments, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Congress on the History of Architecture, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Connecticut Development Commission, 1955-1959, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Cornwall, New York, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Creese, Walter, 1952-1957, 1965, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - D - Da (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - De - Di (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Do - Dw (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Dartmouth College, 1953, 1957-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Davis, E. Fletcher, 1958-1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Denney, Reuel, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - E (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Eldredge, H. Wentworth, 1955-1959, 1965-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Eno Foundation, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Environmental issues, 1965, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Environmental issues, 1972-1973, 1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Environmental perception, 1956, 1962-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Fa - Fo (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Fr - Fu (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Fairfield, Connecticut, 1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
    See also: Series IV, folio
  - Fangeron, J., 1966 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Federation of Student Planning Organizations, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Feiss, Carl, 1954-1955, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Fine arts legislation
    - Correspondence, 1953-1954 Dec, undated (Box 5, Folder 77-78)
    - Laws and bills, 1950-1954 April 30, 1954 May-1956 (Box 5, Folder 79-82)
    - News releases; newspaper clippings, 1953-1956, undated (Box 5, Folder 83-84)
    - Speeches, 1953-1955, undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Foote School, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - French regulations, 1960, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - French regulations, 1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Fulbright grant to France, 1952-1956, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Fulbright grant to Turkey, 1959-1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Fulkerson, Carol, 1952, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Ga - Gi (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Gl - Go (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Gra - Gru (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Gui - Gut (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Garvin, Alexander, 1967-1971, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Goulding, William, 1956, 1960, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Greater North Michigan Avenue Association, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    See also: box 42, folder 700
  - Ha - Hap (Box 6, Folder 99)
    See also: box 42, folder 694
  - Har - Haz (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - He - Hi (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Hol - Hos (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Hou - Hu (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Hammerschlag, Dieter, 1955-1958, 1963, 1971, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Hardoy, Jorge, 1961, 1966, 1970-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Harper's, 1956-1961,1966 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Harris, Walter D., 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 1943, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    See also: box 8, folder 129
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design Association, 1957-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design Student Council, 1961 May 5 (Box 7, Folder 111)
  - Hatch, John Davis, 1954-1955, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 112)
  - Highway Research Board, undated (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Historic American Cities Series, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Historic Charleston Foundation, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    See also: Folio
  - Historic preservation, 1959-1964, 1967-1968, undated (Box 7, Folder 116-119)
  - Historic preservation, undated (Box 8, Folder 120-123)
  - History of Planning Group, 1976-1977-Dec, undated (Box 8, Folder 124-127)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1955-1964 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Hudnut, Joseph, 1942, 1953, 1957-1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
    See also: box 7, folder 108
  - Il - Ir (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Is - Iv (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Institute for Architecture and Urban Studies, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Institute for Municipal Building Officials of New England, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Institute of Life Insurance, 1956 November-December 7, 1956 December 8-1958 (Box 9, Folder 134-135)
  - International Congress of Scientists on the Human Environment, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - International Congress of Scientists on the Human Environment, 1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 137)
  - International Council of Monuments and Sites, 1956, 1964-1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 138-143)
  - International Council of Monuments and Sites: UNESCO Conference, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - International Design Conference (Aspen, Colorado), 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - International Design Conference (Aspen, Colorado): papers, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - Isaacs, Reginald R., 1955-1957, 1967-1971, undated (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - Italian gardens, undated (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - J - Je (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Joh - Jow (Box 10, Folder 150)
  - Jackson, J. B., undated
    See also: box 11, folder 165
  - Japanese National Commission for UNESCO, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 151)
  - Japanese National Commission for UNESCO, undated (Box 10, Folder 152)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, undated (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - Jones, Victor, 1953-1957, undated (Box 10, Folder 154)
  - Ka - Ke (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - Kh - Ko (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - Kr - Ku (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - Kaunitz, Rita D., 1955-1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - La - Led (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - Lee - Lew (Box 10, Folder 160)
  - Li - Lor (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - Lou - Ly (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - Lakeville Council, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - Lampard, Eric E., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - Landscape, 1953-1959, undated (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - Landscape: printed material, 1931-1964 (Box 11, Folder 166)
  - Landscape Architecture, 1954, 1959, 1964, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 167)
  - Legislation, miscellaneous, 1953, 1959-1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 168-169)
  - Leider, Charles L., 1965-1968, 1975-1978, undated (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - Leipziger-Pierce, Hugo, 1958-1960, undated (Box 11, Folder 171)
  - Lowry, W. McNeil, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 172)
  - M - Mal (Box 11, Folder 173)
  - Man - Mi (Box 11, Folder 174)
  - Moc - Moy (Box 11, Folder 175)
  - Mu - My (Box 11, Folder 176)
  - McCall's, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 177)
  - McManus, Ella Burr: estate, 1954-1957 (Box 11, Folder 178-179)
  - McManus, Ella Burr: estate, 1958-1959 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - Man-Made America: correspondence, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - Maps, miscellaneous, 1953, 1960, 1964, undated (Box 12, Folder 182)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1953-1955, 1959-1960, undated (Box 12, Folder 183)
  - Mather, Gurudayai, 1946-1957, undated (Box 12, Folder 184-185)
  - Modern Architecture Research Group, 1950-1955 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Monroe, Connecticut study, 1955-1957, undated (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Moore, Dorothy L., 1959, undated (Box 12, Folder 188-189)
  - Na - News (Box 12, Folder 190)
  - Newy - No (Box 12, Folder 191)
  - National Book Award, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1967-1968, undated (Box 12, Folder 193)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation
    - Annual Meeting (New Orleans, Louisiana), 1958 (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference (Washington, D.C.), 1963 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1966 (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Correspondence, general, 1958-1970 undated (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - International Relations Committee, 1964-1970 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Principals and Guidelines Workshop II, 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Printed material, 1963-1966, undated (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Seminar for Historical Administrators, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 201)
    - Seminar on Preservation and Restoration, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 202)
  - New American Library, 1952-1959, 1963-1968, undated (Box 13, Folder 203)
  - New Haven Citizen's Action Commission, undated
    See also: box 18, folder 285
  - New Haven City Plan Commission, 1956-1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 204-209)
  - New Haven Lawn Club, 1958-1959, 1964, undated (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust, 1960-1964 (Box 13, Folder 211-212)
  - New Haven Preservation Trust, 1965-1973, 1957, undated (Box 14, Folder 213-220)
  - Newport, Rhode Island, 1947, 1958-1960, 1964-1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 221-222)
  - Norton, C. McKim, 1954-1962, 1967-1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 223)
    See also: box 16, folder 256
  - O (Box 14, Folder 224)
  - Okamoto, Rai, 1953-1954, 1960, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - Organization of American States, 1964-1967, undated (Box 14, Folder 226)
  - Pa - Pea (Box 15, Folder 227)
  - Pee - Ph (Box 15, Folder 228)
  - Pi - Pol (Box 15, Folder 229)
  - Pos - Pu (Box 15, Folder 230)
  - Pearce, Anthony E., 1971-1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 231)
  - Pearce, John N., 1956-1965, 1975, undated (Box 15, Folder 232-233)
  - Peets, Elbert, 1955-1960 (Box 15, Folder 234)
  - Personal files
    - Biographical sketches and curriculum vitae, 1947, 1954, 1959, 1964, undated (Box 15, Folder 235)
    - Clippings, 1947-1955 (Box 15, Folder 236)
    - Clippings, 1956-1969, undated (Box 15, Folder 237)
    - Correspondence and memorabilia, 1954-1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 238)
    - Legal and financial Papers, 1943-1968, undated (Box 15, Folder 239)
      General
    - Photographs (Box 42, Folder 700)
  - Perspectives U.S.A., 1953-1955, undated (Box 15, Folder 240)
  - Plimoth Plantation, 1955-1959 (Box 15, Folder 241)
  - Porter, Arabel J. (Box 13, Folder 203)
    See also: box 13, folder 203
  - Potter, Clarkson, 1959-1962, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 242)
  - Pough, Richard H., 1954-1957 (Box 15, Folder 243)
  - Printed material miscellaneous, 1937, 1943, 1950-1959 (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - Printed material miscellaneous, 1960-1975 (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - Printed material miscellaneous, undated (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - Prospect Park, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 247)
  - Pushkarev, Boris, 1958-1964, 1976, undated (Box 16, Folder 248)
  - Ra - Rh (Box 16, Folder 249)
  - Ri - Ron (Box 16, Folder 250)
  - Ros - Ry (Box 16, Folder 251)
  - Rasmussen, Steen Eiler, 1953-1958, undated (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - Reed, Henry Hope, 1949-1955, 1958-1964, 1968-1969, 1973-1974, 1978, undated, undated (Box 16, Folder 253-255)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1957-1962, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 256)
    See also: box 14, folder 223